American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIc. 1826-1836 APS.Archives.IIc APS.Archives.IIc
American Philosophical Society
American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIc
1826-1836
APS.Archives.IIc
American Philosophical Society
1.0 section
This is part of the large inventory for the American Philosophical Society Archives. For complete information concerning this collection, please view the Collection Description.
American Philosophical Society.
- Papers
  - BRACKETED DATES
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Jan. 9, 1826; 12-1/2x8; Netherlands. Ministerie van binnenlandse Zaken en Landbouw
    Scope and Contents note
    The Hague, L.S.: H. J. Van Ewyck. 2p.and end. In Dutch. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Jan.12, 1826; 12-1/2x8; Bataviaasche genootschap von kunsten en wetenschappen
    Batavia, L.S.: Van der Vinne. 1p. and end. In Dutch. ----Copy marked "Duplicaat." ----English translation. Forwards publications.
  - Committee of the Historical Society of Pennsylvania to the American Philosophical Society, January 20, 1826; 7 15/16" x 9 15/16"; Historical Society of Pennsylvania
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. L.S.: W[illiam] Rawle, Jos[eph] Hopkinson, Roberts Vaux. Application to examine documents in possession of the Historical and Literary Committee of the A.P.S.
  - Edw[ard] Livingston to John Vaughan, January 27, 1826; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Livingston, Edward, 1764-1836
    Washington, 1 p., address and endorsement. Will send the A.P.S. what has been published on penal law in New Orleans.
  - Report of the Board of Officers to the Am[erican] Philosophical Society, January 27, 1826; 7 15/16" x 10"; American Philosophical Society. Board of officers
    [Philadelphia], 5pp. and endorsement. D. Resolve that it is "not expedient" to allow the Historical Society of Pennsylvania to copy documents belonging to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Jan. 30, 1826; 10x8-1/2; Bataafsch Genootschap der Proefondervindelijke Wijsbegeerte (Rotterdam, Netherlands)
    Rotterdam, L.S.: J. van der Scallen van Scllenhouz. 2p. and add., end. In Dutch. ----English translation. Friendly letter. Sends program for 1825?
  - Samuel Humphreys to George Ord, January 31, 1826; 7 15/16" x 10"; Humphreys, Samuel, 1778-1846
    Southwark, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 2, 1826; 10x8; Société de géographie (France)
    Paris, L.S.: de Larenaudiére. 2p.and end. In French. Thanks for publication. Awaits publication on Greek colonies in Florida and Texas.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 2, 1826; 10x8; Kungl. Svenska vetenskapsakademien
    Stockholm, L.S.: Fal. Berzelius. 1p. and add. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the APS, Philadelphia, Feb. 6, 1826; 9-1/2x8; Académie des sciences (France)
    Paris, L.S.: Fournier. 2p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Resolution recommending the appointment of a committee to prepare a list of books needed in the library, February 17, 1826; 7 5/8" x 8 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. A.D.S.: F[rancis] Nichols.
  - Peter S. DuPonceau to John Vaughan, March 2, 1826; 7 7/8" x 9 15/16"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S., a volume from the Rev. R. Anderson, of Boston.
  - Isaac Lea to John Vaughan, March 11, 1826; 7 7/8" x 9"; Lea, Isaac, 1792-1886
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. Presents to the A.P.S.: a table of oviparous quadrupeds.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 14, 1826; 9-1/2x8; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S: John T. Kirkland and Charles Folson. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, March 14, 1826; 10x8; Harvard University
    Cambridge, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: John T. Kirkland and Charles Folson. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 16, 1826; 13x8; Collins, Zaccheus, 1764-1831
    A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Ms.comm.to the APS. Natural history, vol. 2, no. 69.) Concerning the Mexican insect, aje. Cf. Minutes, p.551. For letter forwarding the aje, see: Taylor, Sicand & Co. to the Pres.of the APS; Jan.20, 1826.
  - W[illiam] Vaughan to John Vaughan, March 30, 1826; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Sends to the A.P.S.: Royal Society, Transactions, 1825, pt. ii; Astronomical Society, Memoirs, II, pt. i.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, 1826 March; Berlin. Akademie der wissenschaften.
    The Royal Academy of the Sciences in Berlin requests missing issues of the A.P.S. Transactions from Vol. II and VI.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, April 4, 1826; 10x8; Linnean Society of London
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.E. Bicheno. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to R[obert] M[askell] Patterson, Philadelphia, April 4, 1826; 9x7; Royal Horticultural Society (Great Britain)
    London, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: Jos.Sabine. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 14, 1826; 10x8; Caravadossy de Moetz,
    Philadelphia, L.S. 1p. and end. In French. Forwards publications of Turin royal academy of sciences.
  - Report of committee on Marcus Bull's paper on heat from coal, April 14, 1826; 8x6-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: R.M.Patterson, B.H.Coates and Franklin Bache. 1p. Cf. Minutes, p.542. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., III, 1ff
  - DeWitt Clinton to John Vaughan, April 14, 1826; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Clinton, D. (DeWitt)
    Albany, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Forwards to Mr. Vaughan some books and two maps of the Erie canal, one of which is intended for the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the APS, April 14, 1826; 9x7; Royal Astronomical Society
    L.S.: W. S. Stratford. 1p. and end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to George Ord, 1826 April 20/May 2; de Maltitz, Francois
    Francois de Maltitz acknowledges the Society's letter of condolence on the death of Count Nicolas de Romanzoff.
  - Abr[aha]m Small to [Robert M.] Patterson, May 4, 1826; 8" x 9 5/8"; Small, Abraham, 1764?-1829
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Wants the Society to buy the remaining copies of A.P.S. Transactions, n.s., I and II. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 555.
  - J[oh]n Vaughan to Robert [M.] Patterson, May 7, 1826; 7 7/8" x 10"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.D.S. Notations concerning the publication of the A.P.S. Transactions.
  - Ch[arles] D. Meigs to Jno. Vaughan, May 18, 1826; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Meigs, Charles D. (Charles Delucena), 1792-1869
    Philadelphia, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society. Encloses fee.
  - Note regarding the deposit of three rare and interesting maps with the American Philosophical Society, May 19, 1826; 7 7/8" x 8 5/16"; Mease, James, 1771-1846
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.N.S. See Minutes, May 19, 1826, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 554.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Philadelphia, May 20, 1826; 10-1/2x8; Kongelige Danske videnskabernes selskab
    Copenhagen, L.S.: H. C. Oersted. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications. Also, contains card of Mr. Steen Bille.
  - Letter to the President of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, May 26, 1826; 11-1/2x8-1/2; Lambert, William
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Sends rules for locating the longitude of Washington, D.C.
  - John Bywater to R[obert] M. Patterson, June 8, 1826; 7 1/4" x 8 7/8"; Bywater, John
    Liverpool, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents a memoir to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to R. M. Patterson, June 14, 1826; 9x7-1/2; Royal Horticultural Society (Great Britain)
    London, L.S.: Jos. Sabine. 1p. and end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Philadelphia, June 21, 1826; 10x8; Perthes & Besser
    Hamburg, L. 1p. and add., end. Enc.wanting Forwards books.
  - G[eorge] Turner to the Secretary of the [American] Philosophical Society, June 26, 1826; 7 13/16" x 9 7/8"; Turner, George, 1750-1843
    Cincinnati, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: a new theory of the earth, by [John Cleves Symmes?]. Has lost his diploma of membership in the A.P.S. Requests renewal thereof.
  - Letter to George Ord, 1826 July 3/15; Laval, John, Count of St. Petersburg
    Acknowledgment of John Laval's election as a member of the A.P.S., as well as his receipt of a diploma.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, July 15, 1826; 10x8-1/2; Netherlands. Ministerie van binnenlandse Zaken en Landbouw
    The Hague, L.S.: H. J. Van Ewyck. 1p.and add.,end. In Dutch. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 18, 1826; 10x8; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Reuben Haines. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - J[ohn] L[ewis] Tiarks to George Ord, July 18, 1826; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Tiarks, John Lewis, 1789-1837
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Jever, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of certificate of membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Edward Everett to Peter S. DuPonceau and R[obert] Walsh, jr., July 22, 1826; 7 15/16" x 9 3/4"; Everett, Edward, 1794-1865
    Boston, 3 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. In re the deaths of John Adams and Thomas Jefferson. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 556. FILM 199 FRAME 210
  - Letter to Baron de Maltitz, July 23, 1826; 7 1/4" x 9"; Romanzoff, Serge comte de
    St. Petersbourg, Extract from L. 2p. In French. Enclosed With letter from Baron de Maltitz to George Ord, Oct. 6/18,1826. Acknowledges Society's letter of condolence on the death of his brother [Nicholas de Romanzoff]. Cf. Minutes, May 5,1826.
  - Letter to Peter S. DuPonceau and Robert Walsh, Philadelphia, July 26, 1826; 10x8; Adams, John Quincy, pres. U. S., 1767-1848
    Quincy, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Concerning the deaths of John Adams and Jefferson. Film 199 Frame 211
  - Letter to the President of the APS, Philadelphia, July 28, 1826; 10x8; Société royale des antiquaires de France
    Paris, L.S.: L'Abbe Labouderie. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Petty Vaughan to John Vaughan, August 7, 1826; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Has forwarded some books from the Linnean Society for the A.P.S. and George Ord.
  - P[eter] S. DuPonceau to J[ohn] Vaughan, August 8, 1826; 4 7/8" x 7 7/8"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. A.L.S. Work upon various Indian languages. Interesting nature of correspondence with [John] Heckewelder.
  - I[saac] Roberdeau to ----, August 11, 1826; 8" x 9 15/16"; Roberdeau, Isaac, 1763-1829
    Topographical Bureau, Washington, 2 pp. and endorsements. A.L.S. Requests information as to maps showing the northern boundary of the U. S. in the library of the A.P.S. or other libraries in Philadelphia.
  - Letter to the President of the A.P.S., Aug. 12, 1826; 10x8; Southard, Samuel L. (Samuel Lewis), 1787-1842
    Navy Department, A.L.S. 1p. Enc. (see Ms. comm.to the APS. Math.and astronomy, vol. 2, no. 110.) Forwards Lambert's paper on how to ascertain longitude. Cf. Minutes, p.557. For enclosure see letter from Lam
  - Letter to John Vaughan, 1826 August 13; Vaughan, Charles Richard, 1774-1849
    Sir Charles Vaughan thanks John Vaughan for sending him a catalog of the Library of the American Philosophical Society. Sir Charles also refers to the present he has received from Mr. [Roberts] Vaux, a memorial box to William Penn, made from a piece of the Treaty (Elm) Tree, under which Penn negotiated his peace with the Indians.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Aug. 18, 1826; 8x5; Geological Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Thos.Webster. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Philadelphia, Aug. 19, 1826; 10x8; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, L.S.: J. F. Enke. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards publications and asks for APS publications.
  - Letter to [William] Shaler, Aug. 19, 1826; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Resumé of L. 1p. (see APS. Historical...committee. Letterbooks, vol. 3, p.57.) Forwards material for Gräberg di Hemso.
  - Letter to [Bon Joseph] Dacier, Aug. 20, 1826; 9x7; Brown, James, 1766-1835
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p. Copy. Concerning the death of Jefferson. Film 199 Frame 212
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Aug. 20, 1826; 10x8-1/2; Rafn, Carl Christian, 1795-1864
    Copenhagen, A.L.S. 4p.,end. In German. ----English translation. Concerning Scandinavian discoveries in America prior to 1492. Forwards publications. Concerning K.nordiske oldskrift selskab.
  - Letter to William Tilghman, Philadelphia, Aug. 20, 1826; 9-1/2x8-1/2; Rafn, Carl Christian, 1795-1864
    Copenhagen, A.L.S. 2p. Forwards his Krakes Maal and wishes to exchange items with the APS from the Society of Northern Antiquities. Removed from 839.8:R12, Feb.1962.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 23, 1826; 13x8-1/2; Académie des sciences (France)
    Paris, L.S.: Dacier. 2p.,end. In French. Concerning the death of Jefferson. Film 199 Frame 214
  - Letter to [James Brown], Aug. 23, 1826; 9x7; Académie des sciences (France)
    Paris, L.S.: Dacier. 1p. In French. Copy. Concerning the death of Jefferson.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia, Aug. 23, 1826; 10x8; Society of Antiquaries of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Nich[ola]s Carlisle. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication. Film 199 Frame 213
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 25, 1826; 8x5; Carey, Henry Charles, 1793-1879
    Philadelphia, L.S.: H.C. Carey and I. Lea. 1p. and add., end. Forwards volume.
  - Volumes or parts of volumes wanting to complete the set of the Encyclopaedia Francais held by the A.P.S., August 29, 1826; 8" x 9 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. D.
  - Letter to P. S. DuPonceau, Aug. 29, 1826; 9x7; Brown, James, 1766-1835
    Philadelphia Paris, A.L.S. 1p.and end. Forwards Dacier's letter on the death of Jefferson. Film 199 Frame 222
  - Peter S. DuPonceau to J[ohn] Vaughan, September 2, 1826; 5" x 7 3/4"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. A.L.S. "I have resolved on writing to Mr. [Joel R.] Poinsett in order to endeavour to obtain by his means some valuable Donations for the Society..."
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Sept. 22, 1826; 8x5; Huntlent, M. L.
    A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Concerning a donation.
  - D. B. Warden to John Vaughan, Sept. 24, 1826; 7" x 8 3/4"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Librarian of the A.P.S., Paris, 2 pp., address and endorsement. L.S. With regard to distribution of A. P. S. Transactions, V, pt. 3.
  - Letter to R[obert] M[askell] Patterson, Sept. 29, 1826; 9x7-1/2; Royal Horticultural Society (Great Britain)
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Jos. Sabine. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Oct. 2, 1826; 10x7-1/2; Académie des sciences (France)
    Paris, L.S.: Fourier. 1p.and add.,end. In French. Thanks for publication.
  - F. R. Hassler to John Vaughan, October 4, 1826; 7 7/8" x 13"; Hassler, F. R. (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843
    New York, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests Mr. Vaughan to aid him in the sale of some of the books he has written.
  - W[illiam] Gibson to John Vaughan, October 6, 1826; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Gibson, William, 1788-1868
    ----, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Presents a copy of his essay to Mr. Vaughan; a duplicate to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to George Ord, 1826 October 6/18; Maltitz, Franz Friedrich, Freiherr von
    Regarding the Society's letter of condolence on the death of of the Comte Nicholas de Romanzoff, Maltitz encloses an extract of a letter from Comte Serge de Romanzoff.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the APS, Oct. 6, 1826; 8x5; Rivinus, Edward Florens, 1802-1873
    Germantown, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Donates publications.
  - Letter to the President of the American philosophical society, Oct. 10, 1826; 10x8; Société de géographie (France)
    Paris, L.S.: de LaRenaudière. 1p.and end. In French. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to Eyriès frères et cie, Oct. 11, 1826; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, L. 1p. In French. (see APS. Historical...committee. Letterbooks, vol. 3, p.58.) Business.
  - Memorandum, Oct. 14, 1826; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    A.D. 1p. (see APS. Historical...committee. Letterbooks, vol. 3, p.59.) Wrote to Barnet, Barbé-Marbois, Madame de Pusy, Dacier, Coquebert [de] Montbret, and Jullien.
  - Letter to Z[accheus] Collins, Oct. 14, 1826; 10x8; United States. Surgeon-General's Office
    Washington, L.S.: J. [J.?] Brereton. 1p. and end. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Oct. 16, 1826; 8x6-1/2; Collins, Zaccheus, 1764-1831
    A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards publication.
  - List of books sent to the A.P.S., Oct. 26, 1826; 10x8; Academia Real das Sciencias de Lisboa
    Lisbon, D.S.: Alexandre Antonio Vandelli. 3p. and end. In French. Enclosed originally in letter from J.Q. Perina to the A.P.S.; Dec. 6, 1827.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Nov. 3, 1826; 8x5; Lorich, Severin
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. and end. Donates book.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Nov. 7, 1826; 9x7-1/2; Linnean Society of London
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.E.Bicheno. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - P. Pedersen to J[ohn] Vaughan, November 9, 1826; 8" x 9 7/8"; Pedersen, Peder, 1774-1851
    Copenhagen, 2 pp. A.L.S. Will bring publications of Royal Society of Sciences [of Denmark] to A.P.S. next summer. Sends report on Mutual Instruction in Denmark.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the APS, Nov. 10, 1826; 10x8; Society for the Encouragement of Arts, Manufactures, and Commerce (Great Britain)
    London, L.S.: Arthur Aikin. 1p. and end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Nov. 13, 1826; 10x8, 5-1/2x8; Société asiatique (Paris, France)
    Paris, A.L.S.: Eugene Burnouf. 1p.and end. In French. Thanks for publication. ----Translation. 1p.and end.
  - Letter to William Vaughan, Nov. 16, 1826; 9x7-1/2; Bath and West and Southern Counties Society
    A.L.S.: B. Leigh Lye. 1p.and end. Thanks for APS publication.
  - Letter to Mr. Tilghman, Nov. 17, 1826; 10x8; Caravedossy de Moetz,
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French. Forwards volume donated by the Turin Académie royale des sciences.
  - Report of the committee appointed to examine the model of Thomas' marine railway to the [Philadelphia] Chamber of Commerce, December 2, 1826; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: Tho[ma]s P. Cope and four others. "... the Marine Railway may be usefully employed in the Port of Philada... "
  - Letter to the Secretary of the APS, Dec. 7, 1826; 10x8; Royal Astronomical Society
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec. 8, 1826; 11x8; Royal Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: John Geo. Children. 1p.and add: "in care of William Vaughan:, end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Dec. 12, 1826; 10x8; Stockler, Francisco de Borja Garção
    Lisbon, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. In French Forwards volume. For letter forwarding volume, see T.L.L. Brent to John Vaughan; Jan. 9, 1827.
  - Lew[is] Cass to George Ord, December 21, 1826; 7 15/16" x 9 9/16"; Cass, Lewis, 1782-1866
    Detroit, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to Horace Binney, Dec. 21, 1826; 11-3/4x8; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. Contains also Binney's observation on the Magellanic fund; Dec. 22, 1826. Concerning the Magellanic fund and how it may be expended by the Society.
  - [Opinion regarding use of surplus-Magellanic fund by the American Philosophical Society], December 22, 1826; 8" x 10"; Binney, Horace, 1780-1875
    Philadelphia, 3 pp. D.S.: Hor[ace] Binney. Copy.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the APS, Dec. 28, 1826; 9-1/2x8; Texier de La Pommeraye, A. (Arnaud)
    Philadelphia, L.S. 1p. and end. In French. Donates volume.
  - Edw[ard] Livingston to John Vaughan, December 31, 1826; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Livingston, Edward, 1764-1836
    Washington, 1 p., address and endorsement. Encloses an order for the third code of his system of penal law, to be presented to the A.P.S. in his name.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 9, 1827; 10x8; Brent, Thomas L. L.
    Lisbon, L.S. 1p. and end. Forwards gift of Baron da Villa da Praia For the Baron's letter, see Da Villa da Praia to John Vaughan; Dec. 12, 1826.
  - Letter to [the collector of the port of Philadelphia], Jan. 10, 1827; 8x5; Brent, Thomas L. L.
    Lisbon, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Forwards publications to Mr. Vaughan.
  - Letter to the President of the APS, Jan. 10, 1827; 10x8; Société de géographie (France)
    Paris, L.S.: Jomard. 1p. and end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to George Ord, Jan.10, 1827; 10x8; Reale accademia delle scienze di Torino
    Turin, L.S.: Hyacinthe Carena. 2p. and end. In French. Forwards publications. Concerning J. Vaughan.
  - Letter to George Ord, Jan. 18, 1827; 9x7-1/2; Royal Horticultural Society (Great Britain)
  - Sundries paid on account of the American Philosophical Society from, February 1, December 4, 1827; 4 1/2" x 7 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    1 p. and endorsement. D. Endorsed: John Vaughan Esquire. $4.75 for porterage, freight, and postage.
  - H[enry] D. Gilpin to John Vaughan, February 11, 1827; 5" x 8"; Gilpin, Henry D. (Henry Dilworth), 1801-1860
    ----, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning books to be returned to the A.P.S. Presents two of his pamphlets to the library.
  - Letter to General Lafayette, Feb. 23, 1827; 7" x 9"; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. The A.P.S. sends sympathy on the death of Charles Philibert, Count de Lasteyrie. Refers to Franklin and Jefferson. Presented by Arthur Bloch, Dec. 1936. FILM54-67 FRAME73 FILM199 FRAME763
  - Report of committee on Dr. Edwin James' communication on the Menonomie Indians and their language, Feb., 1827; 9-3/4x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    [ca.]. D.S.: Peter S. DuPonceau, J.Mease and Ch.D.Meigs. Eor communication, see: James. Some account...; 1827 (970.1:J23).
  - Letter to George Ord, Secretary of the A.P.S., March 9, 1827; 8" x 10"; Struve, Heinrich Christian Gottfried von, 1772-1851
    Hamburg, A.L. 1p. and add. and end. In French. (Damaged; signature cut off) Acknowledge election to membership in the Society.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, March 16, 1827; 10x8; Society for the Encouragement of Arts, Manufactures, and Commerce (Great Britain)
    London, A.L.S.: Arthur Aikin. 1p.,end. Thanks for publication and forwards publication.
  - D[avid] Hosack to John Vaughan, April 2, 1827; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Hosack, David, 1769-1835
    New York, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S., in the name of the New York Historical Society: [William] Smith's History of New York.
  - Letter to Judge [Charles] Tait, April 20, 1827; 8" x 10"; American Philosophical Society